Guide to the Franz B. Tuteur Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Franz B. Tuteur papers
1940-1989
MS 1576
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.75
The papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, teaching files, and topical files documenting Franz Tuteur's career in the Department of Electrical Engineering at Yale University.
Tuteur, Franz B.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Department of Electrical Engineering, Yale University, 1989.
Biographical / Historical
Franz Benjamin Tuteur was born in Frankfurt am Main, Germany on March 6, 1923. He received a B.S. degree from the University of Colorado in 1944, a Masters in Engineering from Yale University in 1949, and a Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering from Yale in 1954. From 1950 to 1966, Tuteur held academic positions at Yale ranging from instructor to associate professor of electrical engineering. He was a professor of engineering and applied sciences from 1966 to 1981 and a professor of electrical engineering from 1981 until his death in 1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, teaching files, and topical files documenting Franz Tuteur's career in the Department of Electrical Engineering at Yale University.
Electrical engineering -- Study and teaching; Tuteur, Franz B.; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of Electrical Engineering; Yale University. Dept. of Engineering and Applied Science
- Inventory, 1940-1989
  Scope and Contents
  The papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, teaching files, and topical files. The correspondence is professional in nature, dealing with colleagues, students, manufacturing companies, engineering organizations, and publishers. The teaching files comprise the bulk of the papers and are arranged by department name and course number: Computer Science (CS), Engineering and Applied Sciences (EAS), Electrical Engineering (EE), Math, Physics, and Statistics. The contents of these folders vary and may contain homework sets, laboratory projects, testing materials, research notes, and printed material. The topical files are arranged alphabetically by personal name or topic and contain notes, printed material, and scattered correspondence.
  - Biographical material, 1962-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2-12)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
  - Teaching Files
    - New Haven College, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 16-20)
    - Western Electric, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Yale University
      - CS 11b, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
      - CS 11b, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 25-29)
      - CS 21a, 1965-1972 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
      - CS 21b, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 32-36)
      - CS 21b, 1966-1974 (Box 4, Folder 37-40)
      - CS 37a, 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - EAS 10a, 1962, 1966, 1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 42-46)
      - EAS 17b, 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - EAS 20b, 1971-1981 (Box 4, Folder 48-49)
      - EAS 20b, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
      - EAS 21a/CS 27a, 1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 52-56)
      - EAS 26a, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      - EAS 26a/b, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      - EAS 34, 1953, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      - EAS 40, 1962, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
      - EAS 45a, 1954-1971 (Box 6, Folder 61-62)
      - EAS 59b, 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 63-64)
      - EAS 74b, Undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
      - EAS 75, 1973-1987 (Box 6, Folder 66-68)
      - EAS 75, 1973-1987 (Box 7, Folder 69)
      - EAS 75b, 1973-1979 (Box 7, Folder 70-71)
      - EAS 100a, Undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
      - EAS 145, Undated (Box 7, Folder 73-74)
      - EAS 145b, 1978-1988 (Box 7, Folder 75-77)
      - EAS 145b, 1978-1988 (Box 8, Folder 78-79)
      - EAS 200a, 1953-1971 (Box 8, Folder 80)
      - EAS 227b, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 81)
      - EAS 245b, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 82)
      - EAS 301b, Undated (Box 8, Folder 83)
      - EAS 320, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 84)
      - EAS 327, 1961-1964 (Box 8, Folder 85-87)
      - EAS 337b, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      - EAS 365b, 1961-1979 (Box 8, Folder 89)
      - EAS 401b, 1962-1968 (Box 9, Folder 90-91)
      - EAS 420, Undated (Box 9, Folder 92)
      - EAS 444a, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 93-94)
      - EAS 445a, Undated (Box 9, Folder 95)
      - EAS 496/502, 1964-1971, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 96)
      - EAS 908, 1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 97)
      - EAS 984b, 1967-1980 (Box 9, Folder 98-99)
      - EE 10a, 1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 100)
      - EE 20, 1940-1950 (Box 9, Folder 101-102)
      - EE 21a, 1949, undated (Box 10, Folder 103-104)
      - EE 21b, 1950, undated (Box 10, Folder 105)
      - EE 30, Undated (Box 10, Folder 106)
      - EE 33b, Undated (Box 10, Folder 107)
      - EE 43, 1942, undated (Box 10, Folder 108)
      - EE 43a, 1946-1957 (Box 10, Folder 109-113)
      - EE 43a/b, 1950-1952 (Box 10, Folder 114)
      - EE 43b, 1943-1956 (Box 11, Folder 115-119)
      - EE 44a/920a, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 120)
      - EE 47, 1946-1988 (Box 11, Folder 121-125)
      - EE 47, Undated (Box 12, Folder 126-129)
      - EE 111, 1949, undated (Box 12, Folder 130)
      - EE 114, 1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 131)
      - EE 119, 1949, 1950, undated (Box 12, Folder 132-134)
      - EE 121, 1946-1956 (Box 12, Folder 135-137)
      - EE 121/123, 1947, undated (Box 13, Folder 138)
      - EE 122, Undated (Box 13, Folder 139)
      - EE 123, 1949-1952, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 140-142)
      - EE 124, 1964, undated (Box 13, Folder 143-144)
      - EE 126, 1948-1963 (Box 13, Folder 145-150)
      - EE 126/123, 1948-1963 (Box 14, Folder 151)
      - EE 126a, 1946-1950 (Box 14, Folder 152-155)
      - EE 127, Undated (Box 14, Folder 156)
      - EE 137, 1961-1964 (Box 14, Folder 157-160)
      - EE 137, 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 161)
      - EE 145b, 1979, 1987, undated (Box 15, Folder 162)
      - EE 151A, Undated (Box 15, Folder 163)
      - EE 226, Undated (Box 15, Folder 164)
      - EE 227, 1956-1957, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 165)
      - EE 227b, 1988, undated (Box 15, Folder 166-167)
      - EE 255b, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 168)
      - EE 290m, 1966, undated (Box 15, Folder 169-170)
      - EE 290t, Undated (Box 15, Folder 171)
      - EE 337, Undated (Box 15, Folder 172)
      - EE 337, Undated (Box 16, Folder 173)
      - EE 444a, 1981-1985 (Box 16, Folder 174-175)
      - EE 444a/901, 1980-1987 (Box 16, Folder 176-177)
      - EE 444b, 1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 178-179)
      - Math 115, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 180-181)
      - Math 115b, 1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 182)
      - Math 120a, 1980-1983 (Box 16, Folder 183-184)
      - Math 120a, 1980-1983 (Box 17, Folder 185)
      - Math 122, Undated (Box 17, Folder 186)
      - Math 164, 1958, undated (Box 17, Folder 187)
      - Math 222a, 1986, undated (Box 17, Folder 188)
      - Physics 116a, Undated (Box 17, Folder 189)
      - Statistics 260, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Topical Files
    - Antiscience course, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - B-29 turret drive, Undated (Box 17, Folder 192)
    - BMD07M [multivariate analysis], 1972, undated (Box 17, Folder 193)
    - Chernoff bound, 1959, undated (Box 17, Folder 194)
    - Computer Center Operations Committee, 1970, undated (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - Computer needs for educational use, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 196)
    - Computer Science Committee [Abelson committee], 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - "Distribution-Free Pattern Verification Using Statistically Equivalent Blocks," by G. W. Beakley and F. B. Tuteur, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 198)
    - Educomp, 1975, undated (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - Fitch, Frederic B., Undated (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - Gardner, William A., 1975, undated (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - Goldstein, Julius [speech analysis and synthesis], Undated (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - Grades program, [1973], undated (Box 18, Folder 203)
    - Noise anisotrophy [includes writing by Tuteur], 1966-1968 (Box 18, Folder 204)
    - Optimization theory, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 205)
    - Probability theory, Undated (Box 18, Folder 206)
    - Pseudo-inverse, Undated (Box 18, Folder 207)
    - Real variable, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 208)
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institution, Undated (Box 18, Folder 209-210)
    - Ryerson Polytechnical Institute, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 211)
    - Servo mechanisms, 1948-1963 (Box 18, Folder 212-213)
    - Sikorsky Aircraft [digital computer program], 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 214)
    - Theory of games, 1969, undated (Box 19, Folder 215-217)
    - Viterbi, A. J. [error bounds], Undated (Box 19, Folder 218)
    - Watanabe, Satosi [IBM research], 1964 (Box 19, Folder 219)
    - Zapinski, Adean [solutions to problems from Sage text], 1977 (Box 19, Folder 220)